Contact

0989986445 (Mobile) tranminhdtd@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/tran-vuong-minh-091989 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Swift

Objective-C

iOS Development

Certifications

ICAgile Certified Professional

Tran Vuong Minh

Senior iOS Developer

Summary

I am a senior iOS developer with 6 years experience. I have Indepth knowledge of programming language, project management. I have logical thinking and good problem solving skill, dynamic, hardworking and learn quickly new technology.

Programming skills:

- In-depth knowledge of swift and objective-c languages.
- Strong knowledge of OOP, POP, functional programming, reactive programming.
- Strong knowledge of iOS UI, Auto Layout design principles, patterns and best practices.
- Strong knowledge of Restful APIs to connect mobile applications to back-end services.
- Strong knowledge of performance and memory tuning with tools (Instruments, XCode debug).
- Experienced with iOS frameworks such as Core Data, Core Animation, AVFoundation, etc.
- Experienced with offline storage, threading, socket, reactive programming and and performance tuning.
- Experienced with computer graphics library such as : OpenGL, Metal
- Understanding of Apple's design principles and interface guidelines.
- Familiarity with cloud message APIs and Push Notification.
- Experienced with automated testing platform and unit tests.
- Experienced with XCode, svn, git
- Familiarity with continuous integration (Jenkins & XcodeBuild, docker & xcodeBuild), continuous delivery (fastlane, testfilght, deploygate).

Management skills:

- Clarify requirement.
- Identify risk and solve it before it became issue.
- Tracking project.

Experience

Framgia Vietnam
Senior iOS Developer
January 2016 - Present (4 years 5 months)
Vietnam

Start as senior iOS developer, I was joined to projects as iOS team leader and technical leader. Project duration often is one year.

I also is iOS trainer and iOS interviewer.

I also participated in building the CI / CD system for my company.

Viet Nhat Joint Stock Company iOS developer and deputy Head of iOS Division October 2013 - January 2016 (2 years 4 months) Ha Noi, Viet Nam

Start as iOS programmer, after only 6 months I was appointed to team leader because I hard working, learning very fast and have in-depth knowledge of programming language.

Did not stop there 12 months later I was appointed to deputy head of division because I have sense of responsibility and have project management capacity. I also is iOS trainer and iOS interviewer.

Then I quit to find new challenges

Education

VIET NAM MARITIME UNIVERSITY

Master's degree, Industrial electrical engineering · (2012 - 2014)

VIET NAM MARITIME UNIVERSITY

Engineer's degree, Industrial electrical engineering (2007 - 2012)